Assylkhan Abdrakhmanov

247B/49 Raiymbek avenue, Almaty, Kazakhstan

assylkhan.abdrakhmanov@gmail.com | +7(708) 522-45-33

Summary

Back-end developer with 3+ years of work experience in development of web applications and RESTful APIs with Python based web frameworks. Experienced in using message brokers such as RabbitMQ and Redis, Celery task queue. Highly motivated to constantly develop my skills and learn new technologies and tools.

Skills

Languages: Python, C++, JavaScript Frameworks: Django, Tornado Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB Search Engines: Elasticsearch

Task queues: Celery

Message brokers: RabbitMQ, Redis

Tools: Git, Docker

Work Experience

RobiGroup, Almaty, Kazakhstan - 09/2017 to Present

Back-end developer

Project: "UStudy Core" - educational information system.

- Implemented RESTful API
- Designed database models to efficiently store exam questions/answers in any needed format and mode
- Wrote an universal tool to generate exam (test) variants
- Developed utility to construct custom answer sheets and exam booklets
- Configured and used docker to containerize modules of the system

Environment: Python, Django, Celery, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Elasticsearch, Kibana

KexIT, Almaty, Kazakhstan - 08/2016 to 08/2017

Back-end developer

Project: "Azi" - multiplayer online card game

- Designed an architecture of a server application and RESTful API
- Built a server application by using Tornado framework
- Implemented state machine of the game logic
- Integrated a payment system

Environment: Python, Django, Tornado, Celery, Redis, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AngularJS

Freelance Developer - 05/2015 to 08/2016

Project: 3D-printer control software

- Integrated G-code generator "Slic3r" into a software
- Wrote interface for serial communication with a 3D-printer
- Implemented tools for visualization and manipulation of 3D-models

Environment: C++, Qt, OpenGL

${\bf Laboratory\ of\ Mechatronics\ and\ Robotics\ IITU,\ Almaty\ ,\ Kazakhstan\ -\ 09/2012\ to\ 02/2015\ Software\ Developer}$

Project: Automatic license plate recognition software

- Created and trained Support Vector Machine (SVM) model to recognize symbols on license plate
- Developed user interface to control the process of recognition

Environment: C++, Qt, OpenCV

Education

International Information Technology University (IITU), Almaty, Kazakhstan Bachelor of Engineering and Technology, May 2016 GPA 3.55/4.00

Bachelor degree project: Extraction of a depth map from stereo image stream on FPGA

Activities:

- Participation in ABU Asia-Pacific Robot Contest 2013, Da Nang, Vietnam
- Participation in ABU Asia-Pacific Robot Contest 2014, Pune, India